The key to the future is finally unearthed.
Blade Runner 2049 is a science fiction, drama film directed by Denis Villeneuve.
Thirty years after the events of the first film, a new blade runner, LAPD Officer K, unearths a
long-buried secret that has the potential to plunge what's left of society into chaos.
K's discovery leads him on a quest to find Rick Deckard, a former
LAPD blade runner who has been missing for 30 years.
'K', played by Ryan Gosling.
Rick Deckard, played by Harrison Ford.
Joi, played by Ana de Armas.
Sapper Morton, played by Dave Bautista.
Lieutenant Joshi, played by Robin Wright.
Luv, played by Sylvia Hoeks.
Blade Runner 2049 is a 2017 American epic neo-noir science fiction film directed by Denis Villeneuve
from a screenplay by Hampton Fancher and Michael Green, based on a story by Fancher.
A sequel to Blade Runner (1982), the film stars Ryan Gosling and Harrison Ford, with Ana de Armas, Sylvia
Hoeks, Robin Wright, Mackenzie Davis, Dave Bautista, and Jared Leto in supporting roles.
Ford and Edward James Olmos reprise their roles from the
previous film as Rick Deckard and Gaff, respectively.
Gosling plays K, a "blade runner" who uncovers a secret that threatens
to destabilize society and the course of civilization.
Ideas for a Blade Runner sequel were first proposed in the 1990s,
but licensing issues stalled their development.
Andrew Kosove and Broderick Johnson obtained the film rights from Bud Yorkin.
Ridley Scott stepped down as the film's initial director and worked as an
executive producer, while Villeneuve was later appointed to direct.
Blade Runner 2049 was financed through a partnership between Alcon Entertainment and
Sony Pictures, as well as a Hungarian government-funded tax rebate.
Warner Bros., which had distributed its predecessor, released the film on behalf of Alcon
in North America, while Sony handled distribution in international markets.
Principal photography took place mostly at two soundstages in
Budapest over four months from July to November 2016.
Blade Runner 2049 premiered at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles, California on
October 3, 2017, and was released in the United States on October 6.
The film received acclaim from critics, who praised multiple aspects including cast
performances, directing, cinematography, and faithfulness to the previous film.
However, it was a box office flop, grossing $276.6 million worldwide against a production budget of
$150–185 million and failing to reach its estimated break-even point of $400 million.
Among its numerous accolades, Blade Runner 2049 received Academy Awards for Best Cinematography and Best Visual Effects out of five
nominations, and eight British Academy Film Awards nominations, winning for Best Cinematography and Best Special Visual Effects.
A sequel television series, Blade Runner 2099, is in development at Amazon
Studios, with Scott set to return as executive producer.
The film explores themes of future, android, bounty hunter,
artificial intelligence (a.i.), genetics.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.